

CONTACT



Newcastle upon Tyne, UK *Location*



+44 (0) 78155 93011 Phone Number



GARETH@LOWRIE.IO Email



LOWRIE.IO

EDUCATION

COMPUTER FORENSICS – First Class BSc (Hons) Northumbria University 2012 - 2016

A-LEVELS – BTEC ICT Certificate (A*A*) | BTEC Business Studies (A*) | General Studies (C) Whickham School and Sports College 2010 - 2012

GCSEs – 13 x A*-C inc. Maths, English & Science Whickham School and Sports College 2005 - 2010

EXPERTISE

ICT Engineering – (7 x A,, 2 x B, 1 x C) VIA University, Horsens, Denmark August 2014 – June 2015

In my third year of university I took part in the Erasmus+ scheme where I moved to Denmark and studied a variety of modules related to web and mobile application development in an international university.

Living in Denmark changed who I am today through strengthening my perception of cultures and developing both my interpersonal and technical capabilities.

You can find all the modules that I have studied along with grades achieved on my LinkedIn profile in/garethlowrie

GARETH LOWRIE

UI / UX Developer

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm Gareth, an enthusiastic Front-end Developer. I turn beautiful designs into applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6+ React and more. I'm a high-flying guy with academic excellence and a real passion for the latest technologies. Although specialising in Front-end development, I'm actively looking into building full-stack apps with React and Node JS in my free time.

EXPERTISE

JavaScript and Libraries

ES6+, React, Redux, Redux-saga TypeScript, Recompose, Iodash,

Development and Build Tools

git, npm, yarn, Webpack, Gatsby, GitLab, Bitbucket, GitHub, Octopus, TeamCity

Mark-up and Styling

HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SVG, JSON, XML, Bootstrap, FontAwesome

Development Methodologies

Agile, SCRUM

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Front-end Developer | Communicator

Newcastle upon Tyne, UK / March 2018

After training alongside the Product Development Team, I secured the position of Frontend Developer specialising in React.js and became part of a team of three who are responsible for maintaining and developing the next generation of our companies SaaS offering. I am one of two front-end developers working on our innovative new product due to go to market very shortly.

As a team we follow scrum and agile methodologies working to a two-week sprint cycle. To achieve this, we partake in daily stand-ups, and bi-weekly sprint review, planning and retrospective sessions.

We use Atlassian's offerings to track our progress combined with TeamCity and Octopus to push out updates into our production environments.

AREAS OF INTEREST

Fintech

Voice Assistants / Alexa

Artificial Intelligence

Internet of Things

Mobile Development

ACHIEVEMENTS

NORTHUMBRIA UNIVERSITY

I received the Accenture Best Computing Student award for the highest-grade average across all three years of university

PROMOTION - COMMUNICATOR

Through hard work both in and out of hours I received a cross-team promotion where I successfully secured a position as a Front-end Developer

TRAITS

HAVE YOUR VOICE HEARD

I love having my say to influence direction

TECHNOLOGY ENTHUSIAST

I love playing with new technologies

NOT JUST A DEVELOPER

I love being involved in all areas

DRIVE TO SUCCEED

I love smashing my goals

PLAN BEFORE EXECUTE

I love to mock up on my A2 desk pad

INTERESTS



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Product Operations Analyst | Communicator

Newcastle upon Tyne, UK / January 2017 - February 2018

As a Product Operations Analyst I provided exceptional technical support both internally and to customers.

Communicator is a feature-rich highly innovative bespoke solution, that's been specifically designed to be versatile, so that each implementation is bespoke to the individual customer, therefore the technical queries that are received are not repetitive, but are as diverse as their customer base.

Depending upon the nature of the customer's query, they may need support via email or telephone, require a demonstration, coaching, conference call or prefer to discuss their query face to face during a scheduled visit to their office or Communicator's.

A few months in I started working in the Product Development team part-time which gradually progressed into successfully securing a full-time position as a Junior Frontend Developer.

This opportunity has allowed me to develop my knowledge of the latest front-end technologies including but not limited to JavaScript, ES6 and React.js whilst exposing me to working in an agile and SCRUM environment.

VOLUNTARY WORK

Global Volunteer | Restless Development

Tamil Nadu, India / August 2016 – November 2016

Teaching is the best method to alleviate poverty. For this reason, I volunteered in rural India working on projects to improve livelihood opportunities for young people.

As part of a team of Indian and UK volunteers I planned and delivered sessions in local schools and colleges on a range of topics including CV building and interview preparation.

This experience was an eye opener to the cultural differences that are present in modern society. I also developed my communication skills along with my ability to adapt to new and diverse environments.